Inventory of the Dodge Family Papers, 1918-1988
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Dodge Family Papers 1918-1988 1942-1947
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
2008.31
21.00 Folders
This collection dates primarily from 1942-1947, and concerns three generations of the Dodge and Hill families of Chester and Petersburg, Virginia. The papers reflect their involvement in the medical profession, and family life during World War II.
Dodge Family,; Dodge, Anna; Dodge, Emiliy; Dodge, Emily Katherine; Dodge, Henry Haskins, 1922-2005
Information About Using the Collection
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection (1942-1947) chronicles three generations of the Dodge and Hill families. The collection consists largely of correspondence and photographs documenting the Dodge and Hill families and colleagues of Henry Haskins Dodge at the Lincoln Chiropractic College of Indianapolis, Ind. The letters exchanged among Henry Haskins Dodge’s classmates suggest some of the effects of World War II on the home front including military draft and deferment, relocation, and war service.
Arrangement of Materials
The Dodge Family Papers are arranged in three series. Each series consists of folders arranged by the name of the creator (where known). Within each folder, items are arranged by known date.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Personal Name:
Christy, Irene T.; Dodge, Emily; Dodge, Henry Haskins; Dodge, Henry Stacey; Hill, Dr. P. L.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1918-1988
  - Folder 1: Incoming correspondence of Henry Haskins Dodge and Emily Dodge., February 1942-October 1943
  - Folder 2: Incoming correspondence of Henry Haskins Dodge and Emily Dodge., December 1943-January 1947
  - Folder 3: Incoming correspondence of Henry Haskins Dodge and Emily Dodge., January 1947-1988
  - Folder 4: Incoming correspondence of Henry Haskins Dodge., March 1940-December 1943
  - Folder 5: Incoming correspondence of Emily Dodge., July 1942-January 1947
  - Folder 6: Incoming correspondence of Dr. and Mrs. P.L. Hill., April 1944
  - Folder 7: Incoming correspondence of Anna Dodge., December 1918-January 1947
  - Folder 8: Incoming correspondence of Emily Katherine Dodge., February 1944-April 1946
- Series 2: Henry Haskins Dodge work, selective service record, and medical training, 1941-1943
  - Folder 9: Official Permit, Camp Lee Virginia., 1941
  - Folder 10: Grade reports, Lincoln Chiropractic College., 1942-1943
  - Folder 11: Draft registration, Selective Service System., September 1943
- Series 3: Dodge Family Ephemera, 1941-195?
  - Folder 12: Inventory of furniture purchased by Henry Haskins and Emily Dodge., 1942
  - Folder 13: Architectural rendering of family home by Anna Dodge., [S.d.]
  - Folder 14: Women societies and clubs, Emily Dodge and Anna Dodge., 1954 and 1991
  - Folder 15: Photographs of the Henry Haskins Dodge family including Henry Dodge, Emily Dodge, Emily Katherine Dodge, Mildred Stacey Dodge, and Helen Hill., 1941-195?
  - Folder 16: Photographs of the Hill family including Edward Hill, Helen Hill, Dr. P.L. Hill, Mrs. [] Hill, Emily Haskins Dodge, Emily Katherine Dodge, Mildred Stacey Dodge., 1941-194?
  - Folder 17: Photographs of Helen Hill and Emily Hill dressed for the William and Mary May Day Event as well as photographs of the event on campus., 193?
  - Folder 18: Photographs of Henry Haskins Dodge and other students from the Lincoln Chiropractic College (Indianapolis, IN) classes of 1942-1943.
    Known figures include Dr. Bernice Daniel. Probable figures include H. Elton Bell, Arthur J. Schuettler, Harvey T. Miles and Mrs. Marian T. Miles, and Irene T. Christy.
  - Folder 19: Photographs of miscellaneous subjects., 1911-194?
  - Folder 20: Photo negatives.
  - Folder 21: Newspaper clipping, The Progressive Index., July 4, 1937